https://mainemaritime.edu/privacy-policy-terms-and-conditions/

Spring 2021 & COVID-19 Updates
Please see updates for the semester and COVID-19 information here. We are offering limited Admissions tours for pre-registered families, but the campus is otherwise closed to visitors at this time. Thank you for your patience!
Spring 2021
Campus Events: All on-campus MMA events have been postponed at this time. We are transitioning to virtual events when possible. Please see individual event listings for details.
Maine Maritime Academy
A COLLEGE OF ENGINEERING, MANAGEMENT, SCIENCE, AND TRANSPORTATION
Buttons
skip to main content
MenuAbout MMAAbout MMAOffice of the PresidentCollege RelationsConference ServicesEmployment at MMAVisit MMACalendarCampus DirectoryStrategic Plan CloseAcademicsAcademicsDepartmentsAcademic ProgramsGraduate ProgramsHands-On EducationWaterfrontResearchNavy ROTCAcademic ServicesLibraryUndergraduate CatalogAcademic CalendarAcademic Leadership & FacultyEthics Across the CurriculumAccreditationCenter for Professional Mariner DevelopmentCommencement CloseAdmissionsAdmissionsDirector’s WelcomeApplicant InformationI’m Admitted! What’s Next?Frequently Asked Questions for Parents & FamiliesAdmissions EventsMeet The StaffConnectRequest InformationFinancial AidGraduate AdmissionsCenter for Professional Mariner Development CloseStudent LifeStudent LifeResidential LifeStudent ActivitiesStudent Government AssociationAthletics & RecreationRegimental ProgramHealth & Counseling ServicesDining ServicesCampus SafetyCampus BookstoreCommunity StandardsCampus ResourcesNew Student Orientation CloseAlumniAlumniAlumni AssociationBenefits and ServicesEventsStay ConnectedGet InvolvedAwards and RecognitionEight BellsYearbooks CloseSupport MMAGive OnlineWays to GiveAreas of NeedEventsYacht Donation ProgramAnnual Giving ReportParents AssociationAlumni AssociationCompleted CampaignsContact Us Close
Maine Maritime Academy > Privacy Policy, Terms and Conditions
Privacy Policy, Terms and Conditions
Maine Maritime Privacy Policy
1. PRIVACY POLICY
Maine Maritime Academy is a supplier of information about our higher education. We are committed to using the Internet and its derivatives to make this process easier. We are committed to providing you with an Internet experience that respects and protects your personal privacy. Our privacy charter has three promises to you:
We will not release personally identifiable information about you without your permission (except as needed to provide to you the services you have expressly requested). See “9. Third party relationships” below.
You can manage and control the information that you have voluntarily provided to us.
You can tell us what your privacy questions and concerns are so that we can respond.
From time to time new tools and enhancements will be introduced onto the site. Please visit this page from time to time to find out what’s new in relation to these enhancements.
2. HELPFUL DEFINITIONS
Personally identifiable information is information, such as name, birth date, e-mail address or mailing address that can be used to identify the individual.
Anonymous information is not personally identifiable information. Anonymous information is information about how you use our site (such as sites you visit and searches you do). Anonymous information also includes the domain names and/or IP addresses (see “8. Use of IP addresses” below) of Internet browsers that visit our site, the time of day the site was visited, and other non-personal information. Anonymous information is information that is not tied to any person, but helps us know what our users do (for example, the average stay on our site lasts over 5 minutes).
The next sections tell how and when we collect anonymous information and personally identifiable information from you.
3. COLLECTING AND USING PERSONALLY IDENTIFIABLE INFORMATION
You can visit our site and use many of our services without telling us who you are or revealing any personal information about yourself to us. It is only when you register for certain services with Maine Maritime Academy that you will be asked to provide us with personally identifiable information.
Most of our services do not require any form of customer registration, but we do require registration for some services. For example, we ask for information so we can contact you (like your name, email address, and mobile phone number). We use this information in several ways:
to tell you about new features and services available on our campus that are relevant to you
to provide a first and last name on messages you receive from us
to record your visit to certain pages, in order for us to improve the content we provide
4. DISCLOSURE OF YOUR IDENTITY
From time to time we receive requests to disclose the identities of our users. We do not disclose the identities of our users unless we are legally required to do so.
5. ANONYMOUS INFORMATION
We collect anonymous information when people use our site, even if they have not registered with us. We use this information to produce more relevant content, and to improve our services in general.
We will not share any anonymous information about your use of our site with third parties if we know that this information will be linked with your personally identifiable information obtained from another source, unless you have given us permission to do this.
6. COOKIES
A “cookie” is a small piece of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and stored on your computer’s hard drive. Cookies do not damage your computer. We may use cookies to help us provide personal services and to allow you to sign-in to our site without having to enter your username and password each time. Cookies also make web surfing easier for you by saving your preferences while you’re on our site. Cookies may also be used by other companies on co-branded Web pages, as explained below in “9. Third party relationships”.
You can decide if you want to accept cookies by changing the settings on your computer. You can reset your browser to refuse all cookies, or allow your browser to show you when a cookie is being sent. If you do not accept cookies, then some of our features may not work as we intended them to work.
7. SPECIAL TYPES OF INFORMATION
We will not share with third parties any personally identifiable information about you unless you have given us your permission.
8. USE OF IP ADDRESSES
An Internet protocol (IP) address is a set of numbers that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you log on to your Internet service provider or through your company’s local area network (LAN) or wide area network (WAN). Web servers, the computers that provide web pages for viewing, automatically identify your computer by the IP address assigned to it during your session online.
We may collect IP addresses for some purposes (for example, to report anonymous user information and to audit the use of our site). We do not link a user’s IP address to a person’s personal information, which means we will have a record of each user’s session but the user remains anonymous to us.
PLEASE NOTE: Under certain circumstances, IP addresses and/or domain names may be linked to personally identifiable information, when this information is stored in databases managed by Internet registrars or registries such as Network Solutions or ARIN.
9. THIRD-PARTY RELATIONSHIPS
We will only pass on your personal information to named third parties if you expressly permit it and we will always give you the option to decline this.
No third-party sites are covered by our Privacy Policy, but we will make every effort to ensure that third party sites comply with our Privacy Policy.
10. COMPLIANCE WITH GENERAL DATA PROTECTION REGULATIONS (GDPR)
Compliance with General Data Protection Regulations (GDPR) applies to European Economic Area (EEA) visitors/users. In order to complete a requested action for a visitor/user, we may collect and use personal information with your consent. Under certain circumstances, you have the rights under data protection laws in relation to our personal data.
You have the right to:
Request access to your personally identifiable information (personal data)
Request correction of the personal data we have collected
Request erasure of your personal data
Reject processing of your personal data through a third party
Request a limitation on processing of your personal data
Request a transfer of your personal data to you or to a third party
Withdraw or change consent at any time
If you wish to act on any of the rights listed here, please contact us at gdpr@mma.edu.
11. SECURITY
We operate secure data networks protected by industry standard firewall and password protection. We have security measures in place to attempt to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of your user data under our control.
Only certain employees have access to the information you provide us. While we cannot guarantee that loss, misuse or alteration to data will not occur, we try to prevent such unfortunate occurrences.
12. CONTACTING US
If you have questions about this privacy policy or the practices of this site, please contact:
Maine Maritime Academy
Pleasant Street
Castine, Maine 04420-5000
USA
admissions@mma.edu
We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time. All changes will be posted to this page, and we will use commercially reasonable efforts to notify you of any significant changes to this privacy policy.
Top of page
Maine Maritime Academy Terms and Conditions of site uses
The Information on this website is intended to be helpful and informative. However, neither Maine Maritime Academy nor any of its employees, agents or sub-contractors make any warranty, express or implied, or assume any legal liability or responsibility for the accuracy or completeness of any information contained on this site or any web site referred to.
Those who access the site or any site referred to should take appropriate steps to verify all such information. Maine Maritime Academy and its subsidiaries cannot be held responsible for the contents of any pages referred to by an external link.
1. DEFINITIONS
1.1 “This Site” refers to all internet pages in the mainemaritime.edu domain.
1.2 “www.mainemaritime.edu” refers to any organization involved in any part of the design, development, management, response-handling, marketing, promotion or other similar aspects of this Site.
1.3 “User” refers to any person viewing or interacting with this Site, including “you”.
1.4 “Content” refers to any text, photograph or other image presented on this Site to Users by either www.mainemaritime.edu or Users.
2. TERMS
2.1 By using this site, you agree to these terms of use. If you do not agree to these terms of use, disconnect from this site and do not use this site further.
3. SUMMARY
3.1 Except where otherwise expressed, all opinions, advice, statements, offers, or other information content made available through this Site are those of Maine Maritime Academy.
3.2 Maine Maritime Academy reserves the right, but has no obligation, to edit or remove any Content without question, reason or notice.
4. SITE CONTENTS
4.1 The Content made available in this Site is provided “as is” without warranties of any kind, either express or implied, including but not limited to all implied warranties of satisfactory quality, fitness for a particular purpose, title, or non-infringement of any third party rights including, without limitation, intellectual property rights. Maine Maritime Academy does not warrant that the Content will be error free. The Content may include inaccuracies or typographical errors that will be corrected as they are discovered at Maine Maritime Academy’s sole discretion.
5. SITE LINKS
5.1 This Site links to websites operated by third parties. Maine Maritime Academy does not control these third party websites and is not responsible for their content. The presence on this Site of a link to a website operated by a third party does not imply any endorsement by Maine Maritime Academy of that third party or of any products or services advertised, or other information or content featured on that website. Nor does it constitute any assurance by Maine Maritime Academy that that website has in place security measures to protect information which you may submit online.
6. DISCLAIMER OF WARRANTY AND LIMITATION OF LIABILITY
6.1 Under no circumstances shall Maine Maritime Academy, nor affiliates, staff, agents or suppliers, be liable for any damages, including without limitation, direct, indirect, incidental, special, punitive, consequential, or other damages (including without limitation lost profits, lost revenues, or similar economic loss), whether in contract, tort, or otherwise, arising out of the use or inability to use the Content available in this Site or any linked site, even if Maine Maritime Academy is advised of the possibility thereof, nor for any claim by a third party.
6.2 Maine Maritime Academy hereby expressly disclaims any and all warranties, including without limitation, any warranties to the availability, accuracy, or information, products or services, and any warranties of satisfactory quality or fitness for a particular purpose.
6.3 Maine Maritime Academy shall in no event be liable for any failure of performance, error, omission, interruption, deletion, defect, delay in operation or transmission, communications line failure, theft or destruction or unauthorized access to, alteration of, or use of records for any cause of action.
7. INDEMNITY
7.1 You agree to defend, fully indemnify and keep fully indemnified at all times, and hold harmless Maine Maritime Academy, its officers, directors, employees, agents and third parties, for any losses, costs, liabilities, damages and expenses (including reasonable fees) relating to or arising out of your use of this Site including, without limitation, any infringement of any third party’s rights (including without limitation intellectual property rights and rights of privacy and publicity) including any breach by you of the terms of this agreement.
8. SEVERABILITY
10.1 In the event any term or condition of this agreement is prohibited by local or other law, this agreement shall be construed in such a manner as to give force and effect to every lawful provision.
9. NOTICE
11.1 The terms of use shall be governed in accordance with the laws of Maine, USA. The terms and conditions of this agreement are subject to change by Maine Maritime Academy at any time on a prospective basis. Any User’s use of this Site following such notice shall indicate the User’s acceptance of the new terms and conditions. Maine Maritime Academy may provide notice to Users by email or by a general posting on this Site.
10. PERSONAL DATA PROTECTION
10.1 Maine Maritime Academy will store all data including your personal information submitted to this Site.
10.2 Maine Maritime Academy may contact you via email or telephone from time to time to update you about functionality changes and new services on offer. You can opt out of these communications by emailing admissions@mma.edu.
10.3 Maine Maritime Academy is not responsible for privacy practices of third party websites linked to this Site. Maine Maritime Academy undertakes not to disclose any of your personal information to third parties without your consent. Maine Maritime Academy follows strict security procedures in the storage of your personal information to prevent unauthorized access.
11. COPYRIGHTS AND TRADEMARKS
13.1 All Content and materials on this Site, save where otherwise expressed, are subject to copyright and are protected by worldwide copyright laws and treaty provisions. No logo, graphic, text, sound or image from this website may be copied, reproduced, modified, published, uploaded, posted, transmitted, or distributed in any way, without Maine Maritime Academy’s prior written permission. Except as expressly provided herein, Maine Maritime Academy does not grant any express or implied right to you under any patents, copyrights or trademarks.
Copyright Maine Maritime Academy December 2004. All rights reserved.
News
Student Scholars and Faculty Honored with MMA Achievement Awards
MMA Surpasses $20 Million Opening Doors, Changing Lives
MAINE MARITIME ACADEMY | 1 PLEASANT STREET, CASTINE, ME 04420 | 207-326-4311 | EMAIL: ADMISSIONS@MMA.EDU
All Rights Reserved © 2020 • Web issue?Non-Discrimination Notice • Privacy Policy & GDPR
